







Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021

Jump to Section Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Projects |

Summary

A competent professional with 13+ years of experience in Information Technology. PMP, AWS certified solution architect, Design thinking practitioner and Certified Great Place to Work People Manager

Exposure to RBWM Digital Retail Banking, BFSI, Chatbots, Edtech, Search Engine, Leading, Startups, Investment Banking and Telecom domains.

Working as Sr. Engineering Manager for Jio Platforms (Jio haptik) as part of Conversational Al Team. Provide leadership and strategic direction to multiple teams and domain across multiple geographies. Ensure approved staffing levels are maintained, training and cross training needs are met. Ensure that staff has skills to perform tasks through effective communication of goals, objectives, performance and plan. Review, approve and ensure the implementation of new or revised operational processes and procedures.

Work Experience

Reliance jio - Haptik as Senior Engineering Manager Feb 2020 to Till Date

Provide appropriate resources and budget to deliver timely, effective, efficient and predictable payment gateway services and continuing improvement of performance. Respond to operational and business concerns or issues relative to future business programs, projects, or enhancements to ensure consistent delivery of quality services. Ensures own team(s) compliance to goal setting and performance appraisal process Identifying process gaps, provide estimates for business solutions, define the initial scope of the project and manage the scope during the lifecycle of the project. Ensure the project or effort is adequately staffed; trained and managed. Ensure personnel have appropriate skills and behaviors; and effectively communicate performance results as necessary, managing each effort within approved manpower and budget guidelines. Actively lead software engineering team by designing, coding, testing and deploying, and driving on positive change in collaboration with other Development Team Managers Leading engineering team to solution on API management, Microservices architecture, AWS, Mobile technologies

Proiects

Mobility Bot: API Planning & exchange between Chat Platform and multiple ERP of Jio Mobility JioMart Bot: API Planning & exchange between Chat Platform and ERP of JioMart JioHealth Bot: API Planning & exchange between Chat Platform and ERP of JioHealth Ajio B2B: API Planning & exchange between Chat Platform and ERP of Ajio Fiber WA Bot: Interfacing with the Whatsapp business APIs along with access Jio Fiber ERP. Mobility WA Bot: Interfacing with the Whatsapp business APIs along with access Jio Telecom ERP.

Furtados School as Engineering Head

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Jan 2018 to Feb 2020

Continuous Improvement - Establish the software development process in alignment with best practices for Continuous Integration / Continuous Development

Lead Agile Development teams and processes to deliver high quality software

Manage and encourage new ideas from staff to foster improvements through innovations Participate in strategic planning and design sessions with Product Management, Engineering Management, Architects, and Operations

Work with product management and design to define product roadmap

Provide regular high-level communications to the senior management team and represent the DMS development teams company wide

Architecture solutions on API management, Microservices architecture, AWS and Cloud foundry.

Hands on experience in design and deployment of services on AWS.

Hands-on experience in building full CI & CD and auto provisioning of the network infrastructure using AWS cloud formation, ELK., Amazon EC2 Container Services and Jenkins.

Projects

MusicBuddy: Bring the learning online. helps children and adults enhance their creativity from the comfort and safety of their homes. We connect you to our community of exciting teachers, who collectively offers a wide repertoire of creativity development courses.

High Furtados which is India's first and only music education platform and provides all in one music learning solution; currently the product is used by 75000+ students and 3000+ Music teachers.

LearnBuddy (Interactive Digital LSM) which is an Innovative & Interactive learning & teaching product used across 600 schools and by more than 100000 students and 1000+ Teachers across the country with 10% month on month growth rate.

FSM Connect, The 360 degree digital/cloud transformation of the education business which includes CMS, CRM, ecommerce, Payment Management, Billing, Sophisticated scheduling system for registered student and teachers etc. Designed Platform to manage subscriptions of 500000+ students.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Com (Commerce) from Calcutta University in 2003

PG: MCA (Computers) from Sikkim Manipal University (SMU) in 2010

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

CIT PMP

AWS Solution Architect

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Python, PHP, NodeJS, Scala, SQL, C++, C	
SQL/NOSQL Clusters, MySQL	
Postgres, MongoDB, Neo4j Graph	
Kafka, Spark, EMR, Athena, Hive	
BigQuery,Jira & Bugzilla	
Dockers, Cloud Data warehouse	
CI/CD, GitLab	
AWS Services, GCS, EMR, Athena	
SNS, SQS, RDS, Pus/Sub, RabbitMQ	
SNS, SQS, SES, Arura, Redshift	
DynoDB, Google Vision, BigData Tools	
BigQuery, REST, Web services	
Sentry, ELK	
Elastic Search	

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

0 0				
Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
Bengali	Proficient	✓		✓
Hindi				
English	Proficient	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

Projects

Client: Jiomart.com

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: May 2020 - Dec 2020 Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Project Details: Solving queries related to purchase and allowing the to purchase need things. This is done with the deep integration of WA and the Jiomart erp with having NLP in between.

Project Title: Jio Live Chat

Client: Reliance jio

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Feb 2020 - Oct 2020 Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Project Details: Solving queries if the Jio customer using NER and deep integration with the internal ERPs

Project Title: High Furtados

Client: Furtados Music India Pvt. Ltd.

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jul 2018 - Mar 2019
Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Project Details: India's only online platform for learning music.

Project Title: Mauj Mobango Web and App

Client: People Interactive

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: May 2012 - Apr 2014 Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Project Details: community app store with 10+ million downloads

Project Title: Justdial. com

Client: Just Dial

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Feb 2009 - May 2012
Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Project Details: solution architect at Justdial

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent
Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.